Guide to the Stanford University, Academic Computing and Information Services, Academic Software Development Collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Academic Computing and Information Services, academic software development collection
1984-1995
SC0589
Stanford University. Academic Computing and Information Services
15 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Scope and Content
This collection pertains primarily to the Faculty Author Development Project (1984-1986), which sought to encourage Stanford professors to develop courseware on microcomputers. Instruction and Research Information Systems, the division of ACIS that managed the Project, provided equipment and programming support to faculty.
The collection consists largely of binders containing programming instructions, handbooks, manuals, computer disks, and other materials on the final projects. Some examples of the courseware are a theater staging simulation, a simulation of economic and social life in 17th century France, an economics tutorial, and physics simulations. The collection also includes copies of academic software published by Intellimation (1990) and by Kinko's Academic Courseware Exchange (1984-1986).
Access Terms
Stanford University -- General subdivision--Curricula.;; Computer-assisted instruction.; Education--Computer programs.
Collection Contents
- The Theater Game, 1-Oct-86 (Box 1)
- Turing's World, 9-Sep-86 (Box 1)
- Tarski's world, May 1986 (Box 1)
- Faculty Author Development Program, Oct-86 (Box 1)
- Agreement with Project Athena: Philippe (Box 1)
- The Would-Be Gentlemen, 30-Oct-86 (Box 1)
- The Would-Be Generation, 30-Oct-86 (Box 2)
- Hyper Card Academic Training, 1-Dec-87 (Box 2)
- IS + Mac Pass Training Course, Oct-93 (Box 2)
- Mathmatica, Nov-92 (Box 2)
- Mag Reel Sony VI-K: edited master Stanford Humanities Disc, July 20, 1990 (Box 2)
- Mag Reel Sony VI-K: Stan. Univ. Shakespeare Project, 21-Nov-91 (Box 3)
- Stanford Humanities Disc, Protection Master, July 20, 1999 (Box 3)
- American Sign Language, undated (Box 3)
- Shakespeare Project, 4-Apr-88 (Box 3)
- Single frame slide: Stanford Theatre Dept., undated (Box 3)
- American Sign Language: edit sub, undated (Box 3)
- Chemotherapy simulation, 22-Aug-86 (Box 4)
- Economics tutorial I, 30-Sep-86 (Box 4)
- Economics tutorial II, 30-Sep-86 (Box 4)
- Telerana Project, May 28, 1993 (Box 4)
- Video tape: Shogal videodisc premaster tape (beta), n.d. (Box 4)
- Video tape: The Shakespeare Project, Oct-86 (Box 4)
- Video tape: Paris Theatre (beta), July 23, 1993 (Box 4)
- Video tape: Process of Change Laboratory Project, May 1991 (Box 4)
- Video tape: Shogal Laser Disc Project, undated (Box 4)
- Economics tutorial III, 30-Sep-86 (Box 5)
- Economics tutorial IV, 30-Sep-86 (Box 5)
- Heat Exchange in Animals, 1986 (Box 5)
- The Shakespeare Project vision system, July 14, 1986 (Box 5)
- Science for Living, videodisc pre-master, 8-Mar-90 (Box 5)
- Cat demos, dub of edited master (Box 5)
- Physics Simulations 1, 8-Nov-85 (Box 6)
- Physics Simulations 2, 8-Nov-85 (Box 6)
- Physics Simulations 3, 8-Nov-85 (Box 6)
- The Shakespeare Project, July 1, 1986 (Box 6)
- Agricultural Policy Making, 20-Aug-86 (Box 6)
- The Art of Persuasion, master video for RLV videodisc (Box 6)
- The Shakespeare Project, 3 laserdiscs (Box 6)
- AIR Expenditure Statements, 1990-91 (Box 7)
- YOW!, 2-Feb-90 (Box 7)
- Economics tutorial 3, 30-Sep-86 (Box 7)
- Water Microbiology Equations, 20-Mar-86 (Box 7)
- Clearing House for Academic Software Catalog (IRIS), Dec-87 (Box 7)
- Stanford XCMD/tool library, May 19, 1989 (Box 7)
- Faculty Author Development Program, Dec-84 (Box 7)
- Bibliomania, 4-Apr-86 (Box 8)
- The Brayton Cycle, 1984 (Box 8)
- A Respiratory Decision System, June 26, 1986 (Box 8)
- Faculty Author Development Program (FAD), 6-Mar-85 (Box 8)
- Early FAD Project, Feb-85 (Box 8)
- Science for Living - videodisc pre-master, 8-Mar-96 (Box 8)
- FAD Proposals, 6-Mar-85 (Box 9)
- The Rankine Cycle Session, 10-Mar-85 (Box 9)
- A La Rencontre de Philippe, undated (Box 9)
- American Sign Language - 1 inch premaster for videodisc, June 28, 1989 (Box 9)
- 4mm Data Cartridges (ASD):, 1993-1995; (19 items) (Box 9)
- 8mm Data Cartridge: Sgt. Enberg: Bomb handling session, 31-Mar-95 (Box 9)
- Creating Courseware: Faculty Author Development Project. ACIS/IRIS Stanford University, Oct-86 (Box 10)
- Editions of academic software by Intellimation Library for the Macintosh (Box 10)
  - Alias and Alias Student Guide. Developed by Brodie Lockard and the CAT Project, Stanford University, 1990
  - El Mundo de Tarski. Developed by Jon Barwise and John Etchemendy, Stanford University, 1990
  - The TheaterGame. Developed by Larry Friedlander and the Faculty Author Development Program, Stanford University, 1990
  - Turing's World. Developed by Jon Barwise and John Etchemendy, Stanford University, 1990
- Intellimation Spring 1993 Higher Education Macintosh Software and Multimedia Catalog (Box 10)
- Editions of academic software by Kinko's Academic Courseware Exchange (Box 10)
  - Arpal. Developed by Jonathan Burton and Michael Feuer, Drexel University, 1986
  - Animated Waves and Particles. Developed by Dr. Eric T. Lane, University of Tennessee, 1984
  - Appletones and Mozart. Developed by John R. Meier and Jon Appleton, Dartmouth College, 1985
  - Atlas and Overlay. Developed by Carl Spitzer, L. Spitzer and D. Spitzer, Dartmouth College, 1986
  - Bibliomania. Developed by Deborah Murphy and the Faculty Author Development Program, Stanford University, 1986
  - Binary Trees. Developed by John Glen and Mark Sherman, Dartmouth College, 1985
  - Brainchild Grade. Developed by Evan E. Corbett and Sean V. Rome, Brainchild Corporation, 1986
  - BRS Simulator. Developed by The Software Development Group, Drexel University, 1986
  - CLR Anova. Developed by David M. Lane and Brian D. Kluger, Clear Lake Research, 1985
  - Curriculum Comparer. Developed by Jim Kelly, Mathematic Information System, 1985
  - The Data Desk - Student Version. Developed by Paul Velleman, Cornell University, 1986
  - Drexel Plot. Developed by The Software Development Group, Drexel University, 1986
  - Event Tutor and Skel. Developed by S. Maker and B. Meike, Dartmouth College, 1985
  - Drill. Developed by S. Rogers, C. Spitzer, W. Greenburg, P. Bien, B. Duncan and R. Blake, Dartmouth College, 1985
  - Factor ][: Exploratory Factor Analysis. Developed by Richard J. Hofmann, Miami University, 1985
  - Forth Talk Kernel. Developed by Stephen D. Lindner, InSite Computing, 1986
  - FunPlot. Developed by Walter Zimmermann, University of the Pacific, 1986
  - General Chemistry, Multiplan Templates. Developed by Allan L. Smith, Drexel University, 1986
  - GeoStructures. Developed by the Courseware Development Group, Dartmouth College, 1986
  - LaserTerminal. Developed by The Reed Development Laboratory, Reed College, 1986
  - Lesson Writer. Developed by Sally Solomon, Drexel University, 1986
  - LogiMac. Developed by Chris Dewhurst, Capilano Computing Systems, Ltd., 1985
  - Mastering Statistics with Spreadsheets. Developed by Dr. Jeffrey M. Jacques, Florida A & M University, 1984
  - Mechanics: Physics Simulations I. Developed by Blas Cabrera and the Faculty Author Development Program, Stanford University, 1986
  - Modern Physics: Physics Simulations III. Developed by Blas Cabrera and the Faculty Author Development Program, Stanford University, 1986
  - Pascal Pointers. Developed by Jeffrey L. Popyack, Drexel University. [computer disk missing]
  - Personal Resume Writer. Developed by John T. white and George A. Rivera, Bootware Software Company, Inc., 1986
  - Problem Solving Interpreter. Developed by The Reed Development Laboratory, Reed College, 1986
  - PROSE Instructor. Developed by Stuart Davis, Nancy Kaplan, and Joseph Martin, Cornell University, 1986
  - PROSE Student. Developed by Stuart Davis, Nancy Kaplan, and Joseph Martin, Cornell University, 1986
  - Reed Applications I. Developed by The Reed Development Laboratory, Reed College. [computer disk missing]
  - Reed Applications II. Developed by The Reed Development Laboratory, Reed College, 1986
  - Scientist's Helper. Developed by William Menke, Oregon State University.
  - Signal Operations. Developed by Banu Onaral, Drexel University, 1986
  - The SmallGol Compiler. Developed by Thomas A. Standish, U. C. Irvine, 1985
  - SocStat and SocStudy. Developed by The Courseware Development Group, Dartmouth College, 1986
  - Standardizing Recipe Characteristics. Developed by Arthur P. Tolve, Bergen Community College, 1986
  - Standardizing Recipes and Ingredients. Developed by Arthur P. Tolve, Bergen Community College, 1986
  - Student Atlas - Counties. Developed by Robert F. Dahl, MicroMaps, 1986
  - Student Atlas - U. S. A. Developed by Robert F. Dahl, MicroMaps, 1986
  - Student Atlas - World. Developed by Robert F. Dahl, MicroMaps, 1986
  - Test and Questionnaire Construction Kit. Developed by Scott T. Meier, State University New York - Buffalo, 1986
  - The TheaterGame. Developed by Larry Friedlander and the Faculty Author Development Program, Stanford University, 1986
  - TLS: Transmission Line Simulator. Developed by Charles H. Roth, Jr., University of Texas, 1986
  - Tools for Writers. Developed by Eva M. Thury, Drexel University, 1986
  - Torts Exercises. Developed by Hugh Gibbons, Franklin Pierce Law Center, 1985
  - TouchType. Developed by Dr. Janice Wood and Dr. Albert Thompson, U. C. Berkeley, 1985
  - Transforms, Windows, Modulation... Developed by Banu Onaral, Drexel University, 1986
  - Treaty of Versailles. Developed by Eric D. Brose, Drexel University, 1986
  - Trial Quiz. Developed by Dr. Stephen L. Lowe, Minot State College, 1986
  - Turing's World. Developed by Jon Barwise and John Etchemendy, Stanford University, 1986
  - Venn - A Philosophy Tutor. Developed by Richard Wesley and Jim Moor, Dartmouth College, 1985
  - The Would-Be Gentleman. Developed by Carolyn Lougee, Stanford University, 1986